





Last Active: 22-Jan-21

Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects |

## **Summary**

Performance-driven professional with over 7 years of rich & extensive experience in Strategic Business Analysis, Project Management and Stakeholder Engagement

Keen analyst with excellence in gathering and understanding requirements of clients & other multiple stakeholders (at strategic and tactical levels), followed by translation into functional specifications as well as provisioning of suitable solutions Forward-focused Project Manager with exposure in swiftly completing projects with competent cross-functional skills and ensuring on-time deliverables within pre-set cost parameters

Immense success in implementing the RBI new rates policy (MCLR) in ICICI banking system

Rich exposure in requirement Analysis, elicitation & documentation (BRS, FSD), mapping the requirements & translate into functional specifications and test plans

## **Work Experience**

BNP Paribas India Solutions as Senior Associate-Business Analyst Oct 2016 to Till Date

Commodity Products Onboarding: Engaged in on-boarding the commodity products in our application for which we need to generate confirmation and send it to clients for their approval

Equity Settlement Notice: Worked on building the system and work where we send the settlement for EQD deals to end client for reconciliation purpose

Forex Netting Documents for Reconciliation: The project comprised of building the system where BO user can send the netting document to end client which have all the forex deals detail for that particular client in one transaction

ICICI BANK LTD as Deputy Manager-Business Analyst Aug 2013 to Oct 2016

Key Projects Managed: FX Solution (FOREX Trading Portal) Online Deal Booking System (ODBS) Client Tracking System (CTS) Integrated Calculator Treasury Mailer

### Key Role:

Instituting & executing business analysis strategies, making high-stake decisions and overcoming complex business challenges using experience-backed judgment, strong work ethics and irreproachable integrity

Developing project baselines and controlling the same with respect to cost, resource deployment, time overruns and quality compliance to ensure satisfactory execution of projects

Collaborating with clients & stakeholders while keeping them informed of progress and issues in order to manage expectations on all requirements and deliverables

Contributing towards designing activities, including writing functional specifications for product enhancements, as

## **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. well as coordinating with customers for finalizing the requirements

 $\label{thm:engaging} \mbox{Engaging business analysis sessions for understanding processes \& \mbox{mapping them to required business}$ standards

Providing:

- Demo session to business users on product functioning
- Go-live support to each application (L3 support)

Facilitating scope & change management Vs contingency plans
Managing the software development functions involving requirement gathering, development of functional specifications, design & development and co-ordination with customer

Mapping business requirements for process enhancements & translating these requirements into functional specifications and transferring same to technical team

Highlights:

Played a key role in application and database migration from Window 2003 to Window 2012 server Pivotally created Forex trading system in bank for internal as well as external customer Engaged in application compatibly to following browser (Mozilla Firefox, IE11, Google Chrome)

^ Back to Top

#### Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Lovely professional University in 2011

PG: PG Diploma (Finance and Banking) from Manipal Academy in 2013

^ Back to Top

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
MS-SQL			
EDIT PLUS			
Merger tool			
SQL			
Mozilla Firefox, IE11,Google Chrome			
MS OFFICE			
JIRA	7.4	2018	2 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Punjabi	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

# **Projects**

Project Title: Onboarding of payment structure for commodities

Client: BNP Paribas India Solutions

Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: payment structure and netting settlement process

Project Title: Onboarding Of Commodities Product In Application

Client: BNP Paribas

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Project Details: I have been the part of team in which we have onboard the commodity products in confirmation application

for confirmation aspects to end client

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Category: General Job Type: Permanent Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.